## MICHAEL ROQUE

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER













/michaelroque

#### LANGUAGES

SQL **JavaScript** jQuery Node.is **Express** Knex Angular HTML5 CSS3 Ionic v1/v2 C#

#### **PROJECTS**

How 'bout Lunch (7)

This application aims to democratize and optimize the lunch planning process by allowing users to research restaurants using data from the Yelp API, create polls from restaurants in their area, and pass polls to friends so they can vote on which restaurant they want to go to. AngularJS, JavaScript, Node.js, Express, Materialize CSS, D3, Knex, PostgreSQL, API Integration, Heroku, Firebase

## DASHbored (7)

A dynamic, interactive web application that uses data from multiple APIS to centralize most of the tools that people use to either pass the time or stay up to date with the most recent news. Users are allowed to customize their dashboard by selecting which preferences they care about most.

AJAX, Bootstrap, Express, Heroku, PostgreSQL, Knex, JavaScript, Google Maps API, Heroku

### SKILLS/TOOLS

¡Query DataTables .NET **CSS Frameworks** Agile Development **Database Architecture** Pair Programming Test Driven Development

**JIRA** SSMS

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Agilutions Consulting LLC | Denver, CO

April 2018-April 2019

- · Wrote complex SQL stored procedures to format necessary data to display in various portals in admin portals
- · Consulted clients on best solutions for greater usability of platform to meet end goals
- Used JavaScript to build front end UI based on client specifications
- · Designed mobile-based websites for clients with little to no direction from clients
- Demo of projects to clients to communicate progress and collect feedback
- · Came up with creative and efficient solutions in order to complete projects under proposed budgets
- Tasked with frequent schema and code deployments for development team
- · Led strategy meetings for new client projects to identify tech to be used based on scope of work
- Trained new developers to work with netForum platform and pair programmed to reach final solutions

#### FRONT END DEVELOPER

Barventure I Denver, CO

June 2017-September 2017

- · Built responsive and adaptive cross-platform interfaces using lonic framework based on UX designer's specifications and mockups
- · Collaborate with fully remote team to set project scope and demo finished task
- Used Angular to bind relevant data from back end routes and display on interface
- Cooperated with the back-end developer in the process of building a RESTful API

#### **EDUCATION**

**GALVANIZE** Full Stack Web **Development Immersive** 2016 - 2017

Over 1,000 hours of instruction and practice in the NEAP stack (Node, Express, Angular, PostgreSql) to prepare to be an effective member of an agile development

#### VOLUNTEER

## MARINE NUNN **EDUCATION FUND**

2013 - Present

Managing website/social media, building application forms, and responsible for any technical duties.

# MICHAEL ROQUE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER



mycroquet@gmail.com









#### JR. WEB DEVELOPER

Singularity eCommerce Solutions I Denver, CO

January 2014-August 2016

- Migrated scarce, unorganized client data from Excel into MS SQL Server data tables that were organized, rich and clean
- · Communicated needs of clients to development and management teams
- Utilized SQL to manipulate order and product data based on client requests
- Troubleshooted C# backend code, identified issues in the application, and wrote user stories in JIRA to ensure bugs were addressed before version deployments
- Built responsive web pages and email templates based on client specifications and mockups with HTML5 and CSS3.
- · Post-deployment manual QA testing of application based on my written test cases
- Queried data reports and successfully migrated new data structures to ensure product features were implemented for each deployment
- Took on the role of data analyst on development team and handled day-to-day data management and database maintenance
- Wrote frontend JavaScript features to meet client specifications and pass QA tests.